Guide to the J.D. Graham Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Great Lakes Improvements & Lakes Survey, 1854-64; Series VI; 6; (14 boxes)
  - REPORTS, PLANS, MAPS
    - Reports of Graham's Work
      - Report of the Secretary of War, communicating...the report of Lieut. Col. Graham, respecting the improvement of the navigation over the Flats of St. Clair River (Printed at the office of the Nautical Magazine and Naval Journal ), 1856 May 19 (Box 17, Folder 244)
      - Annual report of the progress of works on Lake Champlain, Lake Ontario, and Lake Erie, 1856 Sep 1 (Box 17, Folder 245)
      - "Errata [for S. Ex. Doc. 16, 34 Cong. 3d Sess]....Graham's Reports on the Commerce and improvement of the Lake Harbors....for the years 1855 & 1856" (Box 17, Folder 246)
      - "Maps sent by Lt. Col. Graham to the Bureau of Topl. Engrs. since his superintendence of Lake Harbors", [1857] (Box 17, Folder 247)
      - Extracts of letters regarding government timber at Erie Harbor, [1857-59] (Box 17, Folder 248)
      - Annual Report of...Graham,...on the Improvement of the Harbors of Lakes Michigan, St. Clair, Erie, Ontario, and Champain... (for 1858), 1859 (Box 17, Folder 249)
      - Directions for Water-level and Meteorological Observations, and the registry of Periodical Phenomena by Supt. Survey N. and N.W. Lakes Geo. G. Meade, 1859 (Box 17, Folder 250)
      - Annual Report of...Graham,...on the Improvement of the Harbors of Lakes Michigan, St. Clair, Erie, Ontario, and Champain... (for 1860) (Box 17, Folder 251)
      - "Errata. A complete list of corrections to be made in...Graham's annual report for the year 1860 to the Toporgaphical Bureau..." (Box 17, Folder 252)
      - "Errata. Additional corrections to be made in the annual report of the Topographical Bureau...for the year 1860" and "documents accompanying the President's Message of December 1860" (Box 17, Folder 253)
      - Report of the Topographical Bureau for the Year 1861 (Box 18, Folder 254)
      - "Corrections to be made in the annual report of the Topographical Bureau...for the year 1861" and "documents accompanying the President's Message of December 1861" (S. Ex. Doc. 1, 37 Congr. 2d Sess), [1861-63] (Box 18, Folder 255)
      - "To be attached to the Detroit copy of Col. Graham's annual report for the year 1861. Fluctuations in the elevation of the surface of Lake Michigan" (Box 18, Folder 256)
      - Report to Graham "upon the progression of the waves of the barometer, from West to East, as developed by the accompanying tri-daily observations made at several cities on the Great Lakes", 1862 Oct 13 (Box 18, Folder 257)
      - "...annual report for the year 1862 upon the public works on the lake frontier... for the improvement of the lake harbors, and the Survey of the Northern and North western lakes", 1862 Oct 31 (Box 18, Folder 258)
      - "Instructions for determining differences of Longitude by the aid of signals produced by flashing small charges of gun powder at night", 1863 Jun 11
        See: Oversize, Box 42, folder 724
      - Map of the seafloor off Racine Light House by J. R. Mayer, 1863 Jun 27
        See: Oversize, Box 45, folder 777
      - "Report of Assistant J. M. Bigelow to Col. Graham...upon the...relation of winds and clouds to barometric pressure at Sacketts Harbor, Thunder Bay, and Superior City", 1863 Oct 1
        See: Oversize, Box 42, folder 725
      - "Survey of the Northern and Northwestern Lakes. Annual Report of...Graham...for the year 1863", 1863 Oct
        See: Oversize, Box 42, folder 726
      - "The lunar tide in lake Michigan" [corrections to report published in annual report to Topographical Engineers, Oct 31 1860, including tables], [1863] (Box 18, Folder 259-60)
        See also: Oversize, Box 42, folder 727
      - "Description of the large diagrams exhibiting the actual state of the barometer, winds, rains and clouds at Superior City, Thunder Bay and Sacketts Harbor", [1863]
        See: Oversize, Box 42, folder 728
      - Comparison of water level of several lakes from 1859 to 1863
        See: Oversize, Box 42, folder 729
      - "Monthly Meteorological registers at the fourteen (14) stations", [1863]
        See: Oversize, Box 42, folder 730
      - "Sketch of the Main Triangulation Green Bay", 1863 (Box 18, Folder 261)
      - "Explanations of Tables B2 to B12. Tables of General Meteorological Abstracts", [1863] (Box 18, Folder 262)
      - "Sketch showing the progress made in the survey of Green Bay, its entrances and the adjacent coast of Lake Michigan", 1863
        See: Oversize, Box 45, folder 778
      - Map of Green Bay, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 45, folder 779
      - Map of Washington Island and Surrounding Bays
        See: Oversize, Box 45, folder 780
      - Street map of the Milwaukee waterfront, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 263)
      - Map of Huron Harbor, Ohio, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 264)
    - Other Reports and Papers
      - "Bond of the Illinois Central Rail Road Company and Conditions in reference to the opening in the U.S. South pier at Chicago for said company's benefit", 1855
        See: Oversize, Box 42, folder 731
      - Iron Pile light house to be erected on Coffins Patches, Florida Coast, U.S., 1856
        See: Oversize, Box 46, folder 786
      - The Commercial Times' Third Annual Statement of the Trade and Commerce of Oswego, for 1859..., 1860 (Box 19, Folder 265)
      - Petition of Jean Bapteste Beaubien regarding the transfer of government lands, Fort Dearborn site (Box 19, Folder 266)
  - DATA FROM OBSERVATIONS AND CALCULATIONS
    This subseries is arranged under the following headings: General, Determining Longitude, Lunar Tides, Statistics on Harbors - Exports and Imports. Within these groups material is arranged chronologically, except in the last section where papers are sorted alphabetically under harbor name.
    - General
      - Graham's notebook, "Chicago Harbor", 1854 (Box 19, Folder 267)
      - Graham's notebook, comparison of chronometer readings, 1857-58 (Box 19, Folder 268)
      - Altitude of mounds in Albany, Whiteside County (Illinois), 1858 Mar 25 (Box 19, Folder 269)
      - "Rates of chronometer No. 2557 Sideral & No. 141 Mean Solar From March 1858 to July 31 1859 (Box 19, Folder 270)
      - Graham's journal aboard Steamer Search, 1859-61 (Box 19, Folder 271)
      - Miscellaneous, 1858 (Box 19, Folder 272)
    - Determining Longitude
      This data was used in the 1859 annual report on improvements to the harbors. It is arranged by type, and then chronologically.
      - Telegraph signals between Chicago and Quebec, 1857 May (Box 19, Folder 273)
      - Telegraph signals between Chicago and Racine, 1858 Sep (Box 19, Folder 274)
      - Telegraph signals between Chicago and Toledo, Columbus, 1859 Jan (Box 19, Folder 275)
      - Telegraph signals between Chicago and Dunlieth, Rock Island, 1859 Feb-Mar (Box 19, Folder 276)
      - Telegraph signals between Chicago and Rock Island, New Buffalo, Michigan, 1859 Mar-Apr (Box 19, Folder 277)
      - Telegraph signals between Chicago and Michigan City, New Buffalo, Fulton, Madison, Niles, 1859 May-Jun (Box 19, Folder 278)
      - Telegraph signals between Chicago and Rock Island, 1859 Jun 29 (Box 19, Folder 279)
      - Telegraph signals between Chicago and Toledo, Cleveland, Pittsburgh, 1860 Mar (Box 19, Folder 280)
      - Telegraph signals sent from Chicago, 1860 (Box 19, Folder 281)
      - Time at Chicago, 1858-59 (Box 20, Folder 282-93)
      - Time at Conneaut, 1858 Aug 7 (Box 20, Folder 294)
      - Time at Toledo, 1859 (Box 20, Folder 295)
      - First computations for time at Chicago, Fulton, Albany, and Lyons, 1858 (Box 20, Folder 296)
      - Final computations for time at Chicago, Fulton, Albany, and Lyons, 1858
        See: Oversize, Box 46, folder 787
      - Original computations of the latitudes of Fulton, Ills., Albany, Ill., and Lyons, Iowa, 1858
        See: Oversize, Box 46, folder 788
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and Ashtubula, Ohio, 1858 Aug 6 (Box 20, Folder 297)
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and Cleveland, Ohio, 1858-59 (Box 20, Folder 298-99)
      - Difference in longitude between Toledo and Columbus, Ohio, 1859 Jan 25 (Box 20, Folder 300)
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and Dunlieth, Illinois, 1859 Feb 21 (Box 21, Folder 301)
      - Difference in longitude between Toledo and Elyria, Ohio, 1859 Jan 19 (Box 21, Folder 302)
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and Erie, Pennsylvania, 1858 Aug (Box 21, Folder 303-04)
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and Fulton, Illinois, 1859 Jun 23 (Box 21, Folder 305)
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and Madison, Wisconsin, 1858 (Box 21, Folder 306)
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and Madison, Wisconsin, 1859-60 (Box 21, Folder 307)
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and Michigan City, Indiana, 1858-59 (Box 21, Folder 308-09)
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1858 (Box 21, Folder 310)
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and New Buffalo, Michigan, 1859 (Box 21, Folder 311)
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and Niles, Michigan, 1859 Jun 8 (Box 21, Folder 312)
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and Prairie du Chien, Wisconsin, 1858 Jul 13 (Box 21, Folder 313)
      - Notes on Racine, Wisconsin, 1858 Sep 6 (Box 21, Folder 314)
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and Rock Island, Illinois, 1859 (Box 21, Folder 315)
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and Toledo, Ohio, 1858 Aug 13 (Box 21, Folder 316)
      - Difference in longitude between Chicago and Waukegan, Illinois, 1858 Jun 29 (Box 21, Folder 317)
      - Miscellaneous, 1858, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 318)
        See also: Oversize, Box 46, folder 789
    - Lunar Tides
      - "Tide register at Chicago", 1854-55 (Box 22, Folder 319-20)
      - "Ferry gauge from July 1856 to Augt 17 1857" (measuring height of lake surface), 1856-57 (Box 22, Folder 321)
      - "A register of the relative heights and fluctuations of the surface of Lake Michigan, from observations...on a permanent tide-gauge fixed at the east extremity of the United States North Pier of Chicago Harbor...", 1856-57 (Box 22, Folder 322)
      - Observations of the river gauge on the Chicago River, 1857-58 (Box 22, Folder 323)
      - "Original Table A: A Lunar Tide on Lake Michigan", 1857-59 Mar (Box 22, Folder 324-28)
      - "Original Table A: A Lunar Tide on Lake Michigan", 1859 Apr-Jul (Box 23, Folder 329-329.3)
      - [Table of Lunar tide on Lake Michigan: half-hourly observations of lake gauge on North Pier, Chicago Harbor], 1857-59 Apr (Box 23, Folder 330-33)
        (Table 5 from the 1862 annual report, same as H5 of the 1863 report)
      - [Table of Lunar tide on Lake Michigan: half-hourly observations of lake gauge on North Pier, Chicago Harbor], 1859 May-Jun (Box 24, Folder 334)
      - "A Lunar Tide on Lake Michigan. Table A Continued", 1857-58
        See: Oversize, Box 45, folder 781
      - "Office Copy. Table A5 of the Annual Report of 1862 (Same as A12 of the Report of 1860 corrected)", [1858-63]
        See: Oversize, Box 45, folder 782
      - "For the Topl. Bureau. Table A5 of the Annual Report of 1862 (Same as A12 of the Report of 1860 corrected) and the same as H5 of the Report of 1863", [1858-63]
        See: Oversize, Box 45, folder 783
      - "Investigation of the problem of a Lunar Tide on Lake Michigan" and [Tables of times of moon's meridian transit], 1858-59
        See: Oversize, Box 45, folder 784
      - "A lunar tide on Lake Michigan. Table B", 1858-59
        See: Oversize, Box 47, folder 795
      - Diagrams of lunar tide on Lake Michigan, [1858-63]
        See: Oversize, Box 47, folder 796
      - "Rough copy, in pencil of the Lake Michigan tide register", [1859]
        See: Oversize, Box 47, folder 797
      - "Table A13. Investigation of the Problem of a lunar tide on Lake Michigan. Showing the quarter-hourly coordinates of altitude of the surface of Lake Michigan observed during the twenty-six spring tides...", 1859
        See: Oversize, Box 46, folder 790
      - "A Lunar tide on Lake Michigan. Table D. Quarter hourly observations made at and near the several periods of the conjunction and opposition of the sun and moon between January 3d and June 2d shewing the character of the spring tidal wave on Lake Michigan", 1859
        See: Oversize, Box 46, folder 791
      - "Duplicate Tables of the Neap Tides on Lake Michigan from Jany 1st to June 30 1859" (Box 24, Folder 335)
      - "Original (in pencil) of the averaged observations of the elevation of the surface of Lake Michigan from January 1 1859 to June 30 1859, inclusive" (Box 24, Folder 336)
      - "A table shewing the elevation of the surface of Lake Michigan at Chicago in feet and decimals of a foot, at the periods of the Lunar high and low tides,...January 1, 1859 to April 4 1859" (Box 24, Folder 337)
      - "Tabulation of Spring Tides (not used in this form)", n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 46, folder 792
    - Statistics on Harbors - Exports and Imports
      - Chicago Harbor, 1854-56
        See: Oversize, Box 46, folder 793
      - Detroit Harbor, Michigan, 1853-55 (Box 24, Folder 338)
      - Grand Haven Harbor, Michigan, 1851, 1855 (Box 24, Folder 339)
      - Kenosha Harbor, Wisconsin, 1855 Dec 31 (Box 24, Folder 340)
      - Manitowoc Harbor, Wisconsin, 1855 Dec 31 (Box 24, Folder 341)
      - Michigan City Harbor, Indiana, 1855 Dec 31 (Box 24, Folder 342)
      - Milwaukee Harbor, Wisconsin, 1855 (Box 24, Folder 343)
      - Mount Clemens Harbor, Michigan, 1855 Dec 31 (Box 24, Folder 344)
      - New Buffalo Harbor, Michigan, 1855 Dec 31 (Box 24, Folder 345)
      - Racine Harbor, Wisconsin, 1855 Dec 31 (Box 24, Folder 346)
      - St. Joseph Harbor, Michigan, 1855 Dec 31 (Box 24, Folder 347)
      - Sheboygan Harbor, Wisconsin, 1855 Dec 31 (Box 24, Folder 348)
      - Waukegan Harbor, Wisconsin, 1855 Dec 31 (Box 24, Folder 349)
      - Miscellaneous, 1854 (Box 24, Folder 350)
  - ADMINISTRATIVE RECORDS
    This subseries is arranged under the following headings: General, Property Returns - Harbors, Other Property Returns, and Other Reports, Inventories, Etc. The first section is arranged chronologically and the last three alphabetically.
    - General
      - Legal papers regarding Chicago Harbor construction, 1849-55 (Box 24, Folder 351)
      - Telegraph receipts, 1850-64 (Box 25, Folder 352-54)
      - Agreement for Lieut. J. D. Webster to occupy a government building at Fort Dearborn, 1852 May 6 (Box 25, Folder 355)
      - Legal papers regarding Milwaukee Harbor construction, 1853-54 (Box 25, Folder 356)
      - Copy of a senate resolution ordering Secretary of War to report on the survey of harbors, [1858 Jan 5] (Box 25, Folder 357)
      - Legal papers regarding a Wisconsin lighthouse, [1860] (Box 25, Folder 358)
      - "Copies of correspondence relating to the loan of Dredges by the Engineer Department to Mess. Winams & Co. of Baltimore," 1860-64, [1864] (Box 25, Folder 359)
    - Property Returns - Harbors
      - Ashtubula Harbor, Ohio, 1855-58 (Box 25, Folder 360)
      - Black Lake Harbor, Michigan, 1855
        See: Oversize, Box 47, folder 798
      - Black River Harbor, Ohio, 1855, 1857 (Box 25, Folder 361)
      - Chicago Harbor, Illinois, 1854-63
        See: Oversize, Box 47, folders 799-801
      - Cleveland Harbor, Ohio, 1857, 1861
        See: Oversize, Box 47, folder 802
      - Conneaut Harbor, Ohio, 1854, 1857 (Box 25, Folder 362)
      - Dunkirk Harbor, New York, 1857-60
        See: Oversize, Box 47, folders 803-04
      - Erie Harbor, Pennsylvania, 1857-61
        See: Oversize, Box 48, folders 805-06
      - Fairport Harbor, Ohio, 1857 (Box 25, Folder 363)
      - Grand River Harbor, Illinois, 1854 Aug 10 (Box 25, Folder 364)
      - Huron, Harbor, Ohio, 1854, 1857 (Box 25, Folder 365)
      - Kenosha Harbor, Wisconsin, 1855
        See: Oversize, Box 48, folder 807
      - Manitowoc Harbor, Wisconsin, 1854-60
        See: Oversize, Box 48, folder 808
      - Michigan City Harbor, Indiana, 1855-56
        See: Oversize, Box 48, folders 809-10
      - Milwaukee Harbor, Wisconsin, 1855-57
        See: Oversize, Box 48, folder 811-13
      - Monroe Harbor, Ohio, 1857 (Box 25, Folder 366)
      - New Buffalo Harbor, Michigan, 1855-56, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 49, folder 814-15
      - Oswego Harbor, New York, 1857-62
        See: Oversize, Box 49, folder 816-17
      - St. Joseph, Michigan, 1856-60
        See: Oversize, Box 49, folder 818
      - Sandusky Harbor, Ohio, 1857, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 367)
      - Sheboygan Harbor, Wisconsin, 1855-56
        See: Oversize, Box 49, folder 819
      - Waukegan Harbor, Illinois, 1855-57
        See: Oversize, Box 49, folder 820-21
    - Other Property Returns
      - Chicago light house, 1857, 1859
        See: Oversize, Box 50, folder 822
      - Erie light house, 1859 (Box 25, Folder 368)
      - Inventories, sale statements, 1856, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 369)
      - Steam dredge, 1855-61, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 50, folder 823-26
    - Other Reports, Inventories, Etc.
      - Account of timber and stone needed to build cribs for Chicago North Pier (Box 25, Folder 370)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS
    This subseries is arranged under the following headings: General, Light House Establishment, and Great Brewster Island Sea Wall Project. The first and third sections are arranged chronologically and the middle one alphabetically.
    - General
      - Receipts, invoices, accounts, etc., 1851-59 (Box 25, Folder 371-76)
      - Receipts, invoices, accounts, etc., 1860-65, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 377-82)
      - Account book, with U.S. Depository at Chicago, 1854-55 (Box 26, Folder 383)
      - Checks, 1854-55 (Box 26, Folder 384-403)
      - Checks, 1856-59 (Box 27, Folder 404-18)
      - Checkbooks with Asst. Treasurer at New York, 1857-60 (Box 27, Folder 419-20)
      - Account books, with U.S. Depository at Detroit, 1861-64 (Box 27, Folder 421-22)
      - Account book, with U.S. Depository at St. Louis, 1862-63 (Box 27, Folder 423)
      - Miscellaneous, 1855 (Box 27, Folder 424)
    - Light House Establishment
      - General appropriation for light house repair, 1863-64 (Box 27, Folder 425-26)
      - IRS receipt for salary tax, 1863-64 (Box 27, Folder 427-28)
      - Boston Light House, 1865 May 25 (Box 27, Folder 429)
      - Chicago Light House, 1859, 1863 (Box 27, Folder 430)
      - Detroit, White Fish Point, and Manitou Island Light Houses, 1863 (Box 27, Folder 431)
      - Green Island Light House, 1863 (Box 28, Folder 432)
      - Kenosha Light House, 1863 (Box 28, Folder 433)
      - Milwaukee Light House, 1860 (Box 28, Folder 434)
      - Porte des Morts Light House, 1863 (Box 28, Folder 435)
      - Racine Light House, 1863-64 (Box 28, Folder 436-37)
      - Raspberry Island Light House, 1859 (Box 28, Folder 438)
    - Great Brewster Island Sea Wall Project
      - Financial papers, 1864-65 Apr (Box 28, Folder 439-45)
      - Financial papers, 1865 May-Dec (Box 29, Folder 446-54)
      - Account book, with U.S. Asst. Treasurer at Boston, 1864-65 (Box 29, Folder 455)
      - Account book, with Blackstone National Bank of Boston, 1865-66 (Box 29, Folder 456)
      - Checkbook, 1865 (Box 29, Folder 457)
      - Checks, 1865 (Box 30, Folder 458-64)
- Personal and Family Papers, 1804-89; Series VII; 4; (10 boxes)
  Personal and Family Papers are arranged by person. Each person's relationship to Graham is noted next to his or her name.
  - CAMPBELL GRAHAM (Brother)
    - "Refutation by Maj. Campbell Graham of Col. J. J. Abert's Report to the War Department on the services of the said Maj. Campbell Graham", 1858 Dec (Box 31, Folder 465)
  - CHARLOTTE MEADE GRAHAM (Wife)
    - Letter to her cousin, Miss Sarah C. L. Parker, 1838 Oct 24 (Box 31, Folder 466)
  - J. D. GRAHAM
    - Deeds, leases, mortgages, household inventory and other property documents, 1836-64, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 467-70)
      See also: Oversize, Box 42, folder 732
    - Diary, 1854-56 (Box 31, Folder 471)
    - Financial papers, 1847 Jul (Box 31, Folder 472)
    - Financial papers, 1848 (Box 31, Folder 473-85)
    - Financial papers, 1849 Jan-May (Box 31, Folder 486-90)
    - Financial papers, 1849 Jun-Dec (Box 32, Folder 491-98)
    - Financial papers, 1850 (Box 32, Folder 499-511)
    - Financial papers, 1851 Jan-Feb (Box 32, Folder 512-13)
    - Financial papers, 1851 Mar-Dec (Box 33, Folder 514-23)
    - Financial papers, 1852 (Box 33, Folder 524-32)
    - Financial papers, 1853 (Box 33, Folder 533-35)
    - Financial papers, 1854 (Box 33, Folder 536-47)
    - Financial papers, 1855 (Box 34, Folder 548-60)
    - Financial papers, 1856 (Box 34, Folder 561-73)
    - Financial papers, 1857 (Box 35, Folder 574-85)
    - Financial papers, 1858 Jan-Jun (Box 35, Folder 586-91)
    - Financial papers, 1858 Jul-Dec (Box 36, Folder 592-98)
    - Financial papers, 1859 (Box 36, Folder 599-610)
    - Financial papers, 1860 Jan-May (Box 36, Folder 611-15)
    - Financial papers, 1860 Jun-Dec (Box 37, Folder 616-22)
    - Financial papers, 1861 (Box 37, Folder 623-34)
    - Financial papers, 1862 (Box 37, Folder 635-46)
    - Financial papers, 1863 (Box 38, Folder 647-58)
    - Financial papers, 1864 (Box 38, Folder 659-71)
    - Financial papers, 1865 (Box 38, Folder 672)
    - Financial papers, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 673)
    - Financial papers
      - Account book, with Bank of Metropolis, 1851 (Box 38, Folder 674)
      - Account book, with Pennsylvania Bank, 1855 (Box 38, Folder 675)
      - Account book, with John Brennan, 1861 (Box 38, Folder 676)
      - Account book, with Barney McNellis, 1862-63 (Box 38, Folder 677)
    - Historical and scientific societies, notes and lists, 1853, 1860, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 678)
    - Insurance documents, 1848-68 (Box 39, Folder 679-83)
      See also: Oversize, Box 42, folder 733
    - Legal papers, 1836-59 (Box 39, Folder 684)
    - National Intelligencer (Washington newspaper, two issues, July 23, 28), 1864
      See: Oversize, Box 46, folder 794
    - Papers regarding R. W. Meade's estate (Graham's father-in-law), 1821-55 (Box 39, Folder 685)
    - Photographic portrait of Graham, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 686)
    - Portraits of J. J. Abert and V. V. [McGown] (Box 39, Folder 687)
    - Printed pamphlets and advertisements, 1850-58 (Box 39, Folder 688)
    - Taxable property in Chicago, notes and evaluations, 1860-63 (Box 39, Folder 689)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1804-63, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 690-91)
  - JAMES DUNCAN GRAHAM JR. (Son)
    - Letter from his aunt, Margaret Meade, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 692)
  - LAWRENCE PIKE GRAHAM (Half-brother)
    - Letter from Cpt. S. Pleasonton, 1855 Jan 8 (Box 39, Folder 693)
    - "Sketch of the march of Bvt. Maj. L. P. Graham, 2d Drag. from Monterey, Mex., to Pueblo de los Angeles, California.... July 25, 1848...[to] January 9, 1849" accompanied by a list of places and distances
      See: Oversize, Box 50, folder 827
  - R. W. MEADE GRAHAM (Son)
    - Rules and Regulations of the "Lyceum Society " (West Chester, Pa.), 1852 (Box 39, Folder 694)
  - WILLIAM MONTROSE GRAHAM (Brother)
    - Letters to W. M. Graham, 1840, 1847 (Box 39, Folder 695)
    - Receipts and invoices for supplies for Companies D and K of the 4th Infantry, in Florida (two sets), 1837-38 (Box 39, Folder 696-97)
    - Receipts and invoices for supplies for Company K of the 4th Infantry, in Florida (two sets), 1837-38 (Box 39, Folder 698-99)
    - Receipts and invoices for supplies for Company K of the 4th Infantry, in Florida (two sets), 1838 (Box 39, Folder 700-01)
    - Receipts and invoices for supplies for Company K of the 4th Infantry, in Florida, 1838 (Box 39, Folder 702)
  - WILLIAM MONTROSE GRAHAM (Son)